vaisala.com 2019-08-22

# Vaisala Policies | Vaisala

(Effective as of 2018-09-26, Ref. DOC229710-C)

Your privacy is important to Vaisala Oyj and its affiliates in the Vaisala Group of Companies (Vaisala Oyj and the Vaisala Group of Companies collectively “Vaisala”). This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) sets forth Vaisala’s data processing practices for:  
1) managing Vaisala’s customer relationships;  
2) using personal data of potential customer for marketing purposes;  
3) managing Vaisala’s supplier and business partner relationships; and  
4) Vaisala’s online store operations and Vaisala-operated web sites (such sites collectively “Site”).

Vaisala collects and processes personal data in accordance with the applicable laws and this Policy.

### Purposes and types of personal data Vaisala processes

#### Managing customer relationships; online store operations and the Site

Vaisala typically collects and processes personal data of the contact persons of Vaisala's customers, the Site visitors and the users of the online store. Personal data is collected directly from the customer’s contact person in connection with the customer requesting a quotation or placing an order for Vaisala’s products or services, from the use of the Site or directly from the customer’s contact person through the registration process to the online store.

The personal data collected and processed by Vaisala may include:

  * Contact details (e.g. name, email address, phone number);
  * Other relevant information provided by you when you register to the online store, or order a newsletter or other information asset at the Site; and
  * Information collected of you when you use the Vaisala online store (e.g. IP-address, web log data).

Personal data is used for the following purposes:

  * Providing the products or services (such as shipping the product or making the service available to the customer), and for managing and developing the customer relationship;
  * Marketing activities (such as targeted email marketing and personalizing the Site);
  * Developing services and enhancing user experience (such as by optimizing and personalizing the Site).

The grounds for processing of personal data is either fulfilment of an agreement concluded between Vaisala and the customer, or the legitimate interest of Vaisala which consists of managing quotations and receiving orders, as well as developing and managing the customer relationship, business functions, marketing and communications.

#### Marketing

Vaisala may receive and collect personal data (including e.g. name and email) from marketing data bases provided to Vaisala by third parties or public sources such as Google, LinkedIn, and different business related organisations’ and events’ member and participant lists that have relevance to Vaisala’s business operations.

Personal data is used for the following purposes:

  * Contacting the prospective customers; and
  * Marketing activities (such as targeted email marketing).

The grounds for processing of personal data is the legitimate interest of Vaisala to promote and market services to potential customers. 

#### Suppliers and business partners

Vaisala typically collects and processes personal data of suppliers’ and business partners’ representatives for the purposes of fulfilment of an agreement concluded between Vaisala and the company that the data subject represents.

Personal data is used for the fulfilment of the agreement and managing the relationship between Vaisala and the supplier/business partner.

The grounds for processing of personal data is either fulfilment of an agreement between Vaisala and the supplier/business partner or the legitimate interest of Vaisala in managing the supplier/business partner relationship.

### Transfers of personal data

Vaisala does not transfer or disclose your personal data to a third party without your permission, except when necessary for processing a request for quotation or fulfilling an order, including without limitation, providing necessary information to relevant finance-related companies, logistics and transport service providers and authorized after-sales service providers, as well as responding to your requests or answering your inquiries, or as necessary for protecting Vaisala’s, its Site users’ and/or the public’s rights, property and/or safety.

Vaisala may share personal data within the Vaisala Group of Companies for the purposes described in this Policy. Such sharing may involve transferring data to and from other countries in which Vaisala operates, has business activities or is otherwise present. Vaisala may use third party service providers in implementing its marketing campaigns. For the purposes of the implementation of such marketing campaigns, Vaisala may transfer personal data to third party service providers.

Additionally, Vaisala may share your contact details and online behaviour data, such as Site visits, with sales channel partners for the purpose of sales and marketing of Vaisala’s products and services.

Because Vaisala is committed to protecting your privacy, Vaisala does not sell or transfer personal data to third parties for their promotional purposes.

Vaisala may transfer your information both in and out of the European Union. Such transfers will be carried out in compliance with applicable laws and necessary safeguards, such as EU Commission’s standard contractual clauses, adequacy decisions, binding corporate rules, or US Privacy Shield framework, in order to ensure adequate level of protection for personal data.

### Protecting personal data

Vaisala endeavours to take commercially reasonable technical and organizational measures to prevent unauthorized access to and improper use of your personal data. Vaisala maintains an Information Security Management System to secure information, including personal data. Information is considered secured only when its integrity can be maintained, its availability ensured and its confidentiality preserved. Vaisala’s information security policies and procedures ensure the protection of information from unauthorized viewing, modification, dissemination, or destruction and provide the necessary recovery mechanisms from accidental as well as malicious destruction, alteration or loss. Access to the personal data is limited only to those Vaisala’s employees, directors, officers, contractors, and service providers who need to process the personal data as a part of their duties.

### Retention of personal data

Vaisala retains personal data for a reasonable period of time, not exceeding any legal requirements or limitations. Personal data will be deleted in accordance with Vaisala’s data retention procedures.

### Disclosures required by law

If Vaisala is compelled by law, court order or other judicial process to disclose any personal data to a court or a third party, Vaisala will attempt to give you prior notice using the contact information you have provided. You hereby authorize Vaisala to disclose any information collected of you for any of the above-mentioned purposes, including without limitation, disclosing information in connection with an investigation of intellectual property infringements or other activity that is illegal or may expose Vaisala to legal liability.

### Your rights

You may at any time exercise your right to request access to your personal data and/or right to have incomplete, incorrect, unnecessary or outdated personal data deleted or updated by contacting Vaisala. You also have the right to request restriction of, or object to, the processing of your personal data, when applicable. Please note that by requesting Vaisala to delete your personal data, Vaisala may not be able to provide you or your employer company the products, services or information you have inquired or ordered. You are always entitled to lodge a complaint with a competent data protection authority.

### Cookies

The Site can be used for informational purposes without revealing your identity to Vaisala and without providing Vaisala any personal data.

However, Vaisala uses “cookies” in order to recognize a returning visitor as a unique user. Cookies are pieces of data stored on your computer's hard drive, and not on the Site. Cookies themselves do not contain any personal data. By showing how and when our visitors use the Site, Vaisala can continue improving them. If you do not wish to receive cookies, or want to be notified when they are placed, you may set your web browser to do so, if your browser permits. If you refuse the cookies, Vaisala does not gather any information on your visit, but doing so will require you to re-enter certain information at each visit, or prevent Vaisala from customizing the Site’s features according to your preferences.

Vaisala may link the information stored in the cookies to any personal data you submit through online forms while visiting the Site. Further, Vaisala tracks aggregate statistics, such as Internet protocol address, your computer's operating system, your browser type and the address of any referring websites, and general information about the Site’s traffic patterns and related information. Vaisala collects and processes personal data of the Site visitors to create a personalized Site experience.

### Policy changes

Vaisala may change this Policy, or change, modify or withdraw access to the Site, or the content of the Site at any time with or without notice. The effective date of this version of this Policy has been posted above for your reference. If Vaisala changes this Policy resulting in a material, adverse change in the way Vaisala collects or processes your personal data, Vaisala will post a notice of such change on the Site.

### Contact Details

Your personal data is processed by Vaisala Oyj, a company organized and existing under the laws of Finland whose registered office is at Vanha Nurmijärventie 21, FI-01670, Finland. This Policy is governed by the Finnish law, excluding its choice of law provisions.

You may contact Vaisala at any time in order to check personal data collected by Vaisala. Vaisala can be contacted by sending an email to the following address: privacy [at] vaisala.com.

Vaisala strives to solve any disagreements through negotiations but needs to point out that you have the right to lodge a complaint with a competent supervisory authority.
